Hello friends, students and my dear
investors, welcome to today's master class.
One Guffey sahab once said that risk comes from not knowing of what
you are doing and
today we are going to eliminate that risk forever.
Today we will talk about a
sector which also covers the risk of Indian economy,
tell me who is General
Insurance and its undisputed champion
ICC Lombard because the
results of Quarter Four FY26 of ICC Lombard have come.
So buckle your seat belts.
Because this is going to be a
highly profitable ride.  Let me share with you
the slides.  Let us start with slide
one.  Friends, today our focus is on ICC
Laboratories' Quarter Four F26 results
and we will understand the outlook of Indian General Insurance.
We will understand
how much to expect from their strategic growth.
What is its operational reliability and how has it
become the industry's gold standard IC Labrador?  Why friends are you ready to
decode the gold?  Let's move to the next
slide.  So what's the final word on it?
Come to flat two.  Our core
recommendation is strategically accumulate.
know why?  Because their premium
growth and discipline underlying is perfectly
balanced.  The current market price is around ₹1863
with a massive market cap of near to ₹1
lakh crore making it a powerful large cap
stock.  He has created history by
crossing the cross direct premium income of Rs 28,000 crore in F26.
While
generating a brilliant 19.1%
return on average equity (ROAE).
Quality always comes to the rescue my
friend.  Right?  So now let's enlarge the picture a little.
Look at slide three.  Friends,
India's overall financial services
market is going to be around Rs 750 billion by 2026.
Dollar growing at 11 to 13%
means we should focus on this sector.
This is a growing sector. India's ocean is
very large and global insurance penetration is 60%.
But India is still at 4.2%.
Understand its meaning.  A massive runway for growth.
Friends, the vision of IRDAI is Insurance for
All by 20047.
Friends, this vision of IRDAI becomes
a structural rocket fuel for this sector.
Now look at slide four, general
insurance basically runs on two wheels.
Although it has many wheels, these two wheels are the
biggest.  Health and motor became his
biggest businesses.  Health is Gain Stand alone
health insurance is growing by around 20 taka
friends.  Understand its meaning that some
companies will work specifically on health care only.
Why should I work for the whole world
when I am going to get 20 percent growth here.  And the
second one is friends motor.  Motor is dominance.
Due to mandatory third party insurance, the
premiums here do not stop coming.
Friends, without disease and vehicle,
India cannot function, so definitely the
more people earn, the
stronger the growth of the insurance sector will become.  Now
Global Albert Einstein said
genius is making complex ideas
simple.  Let's turn to slide five.  What can
we learn from global joints like Alia Chap & Jarinj
?  Their sustainable
profits come not from volume but
from underwriting efficiency.
In mature markets, it focuses on the company's margins and combined ratios.
And today, Indian
players are rapidly learning this lesson that
how can we also balance our operating margins and
combined ratios.
Look at slide six, guys.  The
game of PSU versus private is going on in the market.
Because friends, years ago in India there was what
we call license raj, government
companies used to work, so there were
no private companies.  Friends, after liberalization and privatization, private players came and
after 1991, all of them got the opportunity.  On one side is IC
Labard which is trading at 7.5 price to book value
and on the other side
is PSU joint New India Assurance which is
trading at a book value of just 1.1 despite the highest sales.  Why so friends
?  Because ICC Lumbard uses multi-channel
distribution and
delivers superior underwriting metrics.
Growth friends, theirs is strong.  Cheap things are
not always good.  And the quality is
not cheap.  Friends, this is what we see when as an
investor we look at PSU and private
from the insurance point of view.
Friends, there should be more growth in private industry.
Right?  That is why private
players in insurance are getting better
market cap to sales.  Friends, now let us come to the
sub-matrix of insurance.  Flat
intake.  Friends, different industries have
different metrics.  When
you are tracking the insurance industry, especially the general insurance industry, do
not forget to look at the combined ratio.  If this ratio is less than 100 taka
then the company is earning pure underwriting profit.
IC Labard's combined
ratio
is 112.3 annually.  Highly balanced with an operating
margin of 17.5%,
whereas New India is at 115 taka, this means they are
earning 100 and spending 115,
business does not run like this, actually the expenditure
should be 80, but this does not happen in the insurance industry,
but there is no problem,
that is why the insurance industry has two incomes,
one is premium income, let's say there are expenses more than that
and the second income is
investment income, their savings
investment of the day before tomorrow gives them good income,
due to which friends, even if it is 1003, the
companies make profit because
their second income will be strong.  Right friends now
moving to slide nine why is ICC
Labord the gold standard.  There are three modes,
friends, which means they have three walls.
Number one multi line diversification.
Friends, when health claims increased, they balanced it with motor and fire.
As we mentioned earlier, there is
tremendous growth in the health industry.
But when the time of Covid came, who would have suffered the losses
?
Mediclaim companies in the health industry.  So
friends, working on just one point
is good for growth but does not provide sustainability.
When you are in different industries like health, motor, fire, then it is
possible that at
one time there may be more claims at one place,
even then friends, you are saved by diversification.
Friends, their third moat is the fort
wall.  Claims are being processed by Tech First Infra AI.
Lower cost,
higher speed.  Third friends, strong current.
He has directly tapped the customer base of ICICI Bank.
Bank Assurance,
Unbeatable Combination and Friends, because of these three
things, his private share is 9 taka
which is the leader of the market.  That means
ICICI LBA is sitting with the number one market share.
Also, friends, when I look at their solvency
buffers, friends,
you have to maintain solvency of 1.5X as per regularity.
You can see ICC Labard's solvency is
2.5.  They have a massive safety buffer.
Whereas if we go towards round digits then
they have less space.  So friends, this
massive safety net assures ICC Labord
can aggressively absorb sudden catastrophic
claims without requiring capital
dilution, achieving a % return on equity
which is heavily supported by
this float of their investments.  Right?  Now
friends, let us see their results for quarter four.
Let's look at the latest quarter for
F26 report card. Quarterly GDPI was
7340 crores which has increased
by a tremendous premium growth of 17% friends,
7340 crores against 621 crores, retention ratio is improving
at 76.8%
and the most amazing thing is friends, 98%
digital adoption,
98% policies were issued electronically in this quarter.  This is
not just an insurance company, it has now become a tech
first engine, friends.  So, Yes
Friends' quarter four results were
favorable on the top line.  These slides tell the
money story.  Friends, the total crude income is
13.1%.
Remember friends, investment income is also included in the total income, so after
combining both premium income and investment income, their growth was 13.1%.
Despite the pressure of claims, their profit
after tax has grown by 7.3% to Rs 550 crore.  They are
consistently proving that
growth and discipline can go together, friends.
Yes friends, more claims have come.  There
are also pending claims.  But
still their profitability was not that bad, friends.
See the transparency of management in this slide.
Claims increased due to seasonal health illness.  The
loss ratio is at 70.8%
but the combined ratio has actually improved.
111.2%
this quarter.
Yes, this year's
combined ratio was high compared to last year due to higher claims,
but in this quarter,
friends, we have seen the combined ratio improving to a great extent,
so the management was very
clear that we will not compromise on margins to win market share,
this
honesty is what makes a company great, friends, let us
check their valuations, friends,
based on this data, the TE ratio is 40 and the
price to book value is 7.8, which is
at a slight premium to their five-year median.
But The Hygienic is Pristine Zero
promoter pledge and domestic institutions are
continuously increasing their target stake.
Premium valuations are poorly justified
when both your return on equity and
safety are top class.  So what this
slide tells me is the technical outlook.  The
market may consolidate a bit in the short term.
Yes, if it comes in correction then there is good
support below.  But what is the strategic long term
outlook friends?  This is a sunrise
sector.  We will get good growth,
better than the overall Indian economy.  So we can
accumulate on tips.  This is the best vehicle to
play India's financialization of savings theme,
friend.
Let me take you to the fair value of
this company.  Friends, we already saw some
company.  Like we just saw New India
Insurance.  Look, this is the
long term chart of New India Insurance.  This means that
overall investors have not earned any money
from 2017 till now.  Why?
We also saw the reason for that.  Now on the other hand we have Star Health
which is in stand alone health care.
Friends, the situation is bad.  Let me check
ICicibard
here.  ICICI GI Right You Can See Friends
ICICI GI has made investors earn money.
We have also seen a rally since the IPO.
Also saw major corrections in between.
Friends, accumulation should be done in every correction.  This is
definitely an industry that
we can see from here.  Friends, what I just
discussed with you guys is C Long
Term Premium Growth, this is the company which had a
turnover of only Rs 208 crores in 2003.
Turnover of Rs 6000 crore in 213.
Before that he had also made losses for two years.  But
today, if we look at 2026, we have reached a turnover of Rs 3000 crore.
Friends, he made a profit of Rs 2800
crores.  Yes, we agree that
they made losses in 20121.  After that friends,
he never suffered any loss.  Friends,
due to the consistent profitability of the company, the
company's continued growth.
Despite of near to 25% of
dividend distribution.  Friends, if I
look at the trend of this year, there was
only a growth of one and a half rupees in quarter one.  That means
friends, understand that the growth was not good.  This
growth cannot be given to us in our lifetime.
But yes, the profit was tremendous. If
we look at the results of the month i.e. the results of quarter three, then
friends the growth was improving. You must be
aware that the effect of GST came and
friends GST started bringing growth. Less
GST, more policy profitability,
but in the month friends, their margins decreased, their
margins were broken. Similarly,
when we saw for F26, the growth has given further improvement. There has been good growth but the profitability has broken further. Friends, on the basis of this data, when
I see their trailing P,
friends, last year's EPS was 51.  T
was 35 of these.  Now my EPS 56 has arrived.  That
means my earnings have increased.
My valuations have decreased.  That means yes friends,
we are coming towards favourable valuations.
I am not expecting much growth next year.
This year I am
expecting good growth in premium of 11
taka.  But we will see profits increase once the
margins improve.  Currently the margins are
in challenging mode so I am
not expecting any profit this year.  You can see
friends, I hope this company will
cross Rs 500 crore in 2030.  The
premium will cross Rs 1 lakh crore in 2035.  Friends, then this same
company will be making a profit of Rs 8000 crore
and I hope that my fair
value will be around Rs 5900 at that time.  So yes
friends, for the long term
we can definitely take such a company.  I have
given the weightage here which is the weightage of our main fund.
We have
increased the weightage here a little due to improvement in premium.  But the
valuation is not so favourable.  You
can see the fair value friends is 2200.  And right
now it's a little closer to fair value.   It is
not very expensive and not very cheap either.
So friends, on the basis of these valuations,
we have also kept cash.  This is what it can
plan.  So friends I am back to the
presentation final slide the synthesis my
tailwind 750 billion dollar industry is
under penetrated so growth has to be achieved
meeting flawless micro execution
combined ratio of 112 98% digital policy
all these are good signs friends ICC
Lombard friends yes it is
not just a part of India's growth story, it is defining the
gold standard of the sector through its discipline under writing.
So thank you very much
for joining today's deep time.  Hope
you learn something that stays with you forever.
Before I Conclude Friends
Disclaimer Right.  So before we sign up a
mandatory disclaimer.  This presentation and
whole report are for educational purposes only
and do not constitute direct financial
advice.  Investing in the stock market
involves risk.  Please note we are a SEBI
registered investor advisory company.  But we
highly recommend checking the data on your own
before you invest in any company.